

□ (530) 356-7734 | Sojoey.mckenzie27@gmail.com | Afjoeymckenzie.tech | DoeyMcKenzie | DoeyMcKen

Summary_

Seasoned developer with diverse experience building enterprise-grade distributed software systems primarily with technologies in .NET, Java and TypeScript in industries including healthcare, insurance, manufacturing, and fintech. I specialize in building fast, efficient web-based services and APIs, software architecture and design, software leadership and mentorship, and delivering high quality software products at nationwide scale.

I am an avid contributor to open source and technology communities primarily in the Rust and TypeScript alongside minor contributions in Go. I enjoy dispersing knowledge and experience with other like minded developers that share a similar passion for software development. I write and produce technical content available on my blog, Twitch, and YouTube exploring emerging technologies with a focus on developer relations.

Experience

National Funding

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2022 - Present

- Developing .NET microservices, React applications with Next.js, and AWS infrastructure supporting financial operations
- Integrating external financial partner APIs into backend systems, increasing customer lending conversion by up to 50%
- Managing CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with AWS, Terraform, Jenkins, and containerized workflows with Docker
- · Upgrading internal .NET infrastructure improving performance and speed by 30% while reducing AWS costs
- Troubleshooting applications errors using log aggregation services with OpenSearch and Kibana
- · Led company-wide modernization efforts to develop publicly available APIs for consumers in the fintech space

MediKeeper

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2020 - Jan. 2022

- Developed .NET and JavaScript applications with Vue deployed to Azure infrastructure
- · Iterated on **UX** with product designers to increase user retention and impression conversion rates
- Created CI/CD pipelines and automated processes with Azure DevOps to improve existing build times
- Administered SQL Server and Oracle databases while improving business critical query times by up to 60%
- · Improved existing system architecture by migrating legacy .NET Framework applications to modern .NET
- Maintained integration suites with JavaScript and Cypress to automate platform testing, increasing QA velocity by 20%

Sierra Pacific Industries Redding, CA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- · Developed internal applications and dashboards using modern RPG ILE on the IBM iSeries AS/400 and .NET for desktop applications
- · Migrated brownfield and legacy applications to modern RPG architectures increasing application response times
- Improved business critical PL/SQL queries for embedded systems by up to 40% in several applications
- · Administered system tasks on the IBM iSeries AS/400 to maintain environmental integrity increase system up-time
- Managed database schemas with **SQL Server** using **SSMS** to support inventory management operations

VSP Global Sacramento, CA

• Developed Java APIs and Angular applications with TypeScript for nationwide use by optometry offices and retailers

- Migrated JEE and Spring applications to Spring Boot while increasing response times by up to 25% · Lead development of Angular applications utilizing Angular Material, SCSS, NgRx, and modern web standards
- Created and maintained CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins deployed to AWS hosting infrastructure
- · Administrated systems and servers while migrating non-production workloads off legacy Windows servers to Linux servers
- · Assisted in troubleshooting company-wide service outages and application performance issues with Splunk and Wily

Engility Corporation San Diego, CA

OPERATIONS RESEARCH ANALYST

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sept. 2016 - May. 2018

Jun. 2018 - Jan. 2020

- · Wrote and maintained VBA and R codebases to perform data analysis and spreadsheet specific functionality
- · Provided contractor support for U.S. Department of Defense naval programs for systems engineering and data analysis
- · Performed regression analysis and statistical programming using R to refine estimated financial expenditure models
- Managed automated Excel spreadsheets and codebases in RStudio for data analysis and exploration
- Maintained databases of financial data and provided ad hoc SQL reporting for various projects

Education

San Diego State University

San Diego, CA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ASTROPHYSICS, MINOR IN MATHEMATICS

May 2016

· Coursework included training in: scientific computation, procedural and object-oriented programming, advanced mathematics, physics, astronomy, data structures, and numerical algorithms with thesis on computational photometry for stellar astrophysics